

Rasmus Arpe Fogh Egebæk

https://arpe.me - rasmus.arpe@gmail.com - +45 30 48 59 57 - https://github.com/Rasmusafj

29-year old passionate programmer currently looking for new opportunities as a (Senior) Machine Learning Engineer or Data Scientist. I thrive at solving complex problems with a vast amount of mathematics and programming involved. Read more about me at https://arpe.me.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Alvenir Dec 2021–Jul 2022

Chief Technical Officer

- Architect and developer of a cloud native platform for speech recognition with horizontal scaling, multiple languages and customizable inference pipelines with multiple task specific modules.
- Training of machine learning models for Automatic Speech Recognition and various Natural Language Processing tasks.
- Data mining of machine learning training data such as text, speech and audio.

Technical University of Denmark

Dec 2020-Nov 2021

Research Assistant

- Research within Automatic Speech Recognition, prototyping and business development of the speech recognition company Alvenir. Funded by InnoExplorer grant from Innovation Fund Denmark.

Technologies used: Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Huggingface, Transformers, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Helmfile, FastAPI, Kafka, GCP, AWS, Django, Angular, Postgresql, Fairseq, KenLM, Scikit-learn etc.

Netcompany Sep 2019–Nov 2020

IT Consultant

- Software development as an IT consultant on various projects ranging from 5-100+ participants.

Technologies used: Kafka, Angular, SQL, Java, Groovy, Kotlin, Spring, Hibernate, Ebean, Flyway, Liquibase, Gradle, Git, REST, SOAP, AWS, Docker, Openshift, Terraform etc.

Technical University of Denmark

Jul 2019-Aug 2019

Research Assistant

- Open-sourcing of Deep Speech 2 Automatic Speech Recognition models for Danish.
- Multiple experiments such as multilingual Automatic Speech Recognition, distillation of large deep learning models and Unidirectional Automatic Speech Recognition models for real time inference.

During studies 2015–2019

Analyst, Netcompany - Development of business logic code in large IT systems in Java.

Teaching Assistant, Technical University of Denmark - Assisting students in the course Database Systems

Teaching Assistant, Technical University of Denmark - Assisting students in the course Social data analysis and visualization

EDUCATION

Technical University of Denmark, DTU

2013-2019

Digital Media Engineering (M.Sc.) - GPA: 11.4

Thesis: DanSpeech: Building an Open-Source Speech Recognition Tool for Danish - Grade 12

Computer Science Engineering (B.Sc.) - GPA: 9.7

Thesis: Efficient Feedback Analysis using Recurrent Neural Networks - Grade 12